In the last video, I talked
在上一节课中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
about how when faced with
我讲到了应当怎样面对
a machine learning problem, there are
机器学习问题
often lots of different ideas on how to improve the algorithm.
有很多提高算法表现的方法
In this video let's
在本次课程中
talk about the concepts of error
我们将会讲到
analysis which will help
误差分析（error analysis）的概念
me give you a way to more
这会帮助你
systematically make some of these decisions.
更系统地做出决定
If you're starting work on a
如果你准备
machine learning product or building
研究机器学习的东西
a machine learning application, it is
或者构造机器学习应用程序
often considered very good practice
最好的实践方法
to start, not by building
不是建立一个
a very complicated system with
非常复杂的系统
lots of complex features and so
拥有多么复杂的变量
on, but to instead start
而是
by building a very simple
构建一个简单的算法
algorithm, the you can implement quickly.
这样你可以很快地实现它
And when I start on
每当我研究
a learning problem, what I usually
机器学习的问题时
do is spend at most one
我最多只会花一天的时间
day, literally at most 24
就是字面意义上的24小时
hours to try to get something really quick and dirty.
来试图很快的把结果搞出来 即便效果不好
Frankly not at all sophisticated system.
坦白的说 就是根本没有用复杂的系统
But get something really quick and
但是只是很快的得到的结果
dirty running and implement
即便运行得不完美
it and then test it on
但是也把它运行一遍
my cross validation data. Once
最后通过交叉验证来检验数据
you've done that, you can
一旦做完
then plot learning curves.
你可以画出学习曲线
This is what we talked about in the previous set of videos.
这个我们在前面的课程中已经讲过了
But plot learning curves of the
通过画出学习曲线
training and test errors to
以及检验误差
try to figure out if your
来找出
learning algorithm may be suffering
你的算法是否有
from high bias or high
高偏差和高方差的问题
variance or something else and
或者别的问题
use that to try to
在这样分析之后
decide if having more data
再来决定用更多的数据训练
and more features and so on are likely to help.
或者加入更多的特征变量是否有用
And the reason that this
这么做的原因是
is a good approach is often
这在你刚接触机器学习问题时
when you're just starting out on
是一个很好的方法
a learning problem, there's really no
你并不能
way to tell in advance
提前知道
whether you need more complex
你是否需要复杂的特征变量
features or whether you need
或者你是否需要
more data or something else.
更多的数据 还是别的什么
And it's just very hard to tell
提前知道你应该做什么
in advance, that is in
是非常难的
the absence of evidence, in
因为你缺少证据
the absence of seeing a
缺少学习曲线
learning curve, it's just incredibly
因此 你很难知道
difficult to figure out where you should be spending your time.
你应该把时间花在什么地方来提高算法的表现
And it's often by implementing even
但是当你实践一个
a very, very quick and dirty
非常简单即便不完美的
implementation and by plotting
方法时
learning curves that that helps you make these decisions.
你可以通过画出学习曲线来做出进一步的选择
So if you like, you can think
你可以
of this as a way of
用这种方式
avoiding what's sometimes called
来避免一种
premature optimization in computer programming.
电脑编程里的过早优化问题
And this is idea that just
这种理念是
says that we should let
我们必须
evidence guide our decisions
用证据来领导我们的决策
on where to spend our time
怎样分配自己的时间来优化算法
rather than use gut feeling,
而不是仅仅凭直觉
which is often wrong.
凭直觉得出的东西一般总是错误的
In addition to plotting learning
除了画出学习曲线之外
curves, one other thing
一件非常有用的事是
that's often very useful to do is what's called error analysis.
误差分析
And what I mean by that is
我的意思是说
that when building, say
当我们在构造
a spam classifier, I will
比如构造垃圾邮件分类器时
often look at my
我会看一看
cross validation set and manually
我的交叉验证数据集
look at the emails that my
然后亲自看一看
algorithm is making errors on.
哪些邮件被算法错误地分类
So, look at the spam emails
因此 通过这些
and non-spam emails that the
被算法错误分类的垃圾邮件
algorithm is misclassifying, and see
与非垃圾邮件
if you can spot any systematic
你可以发现某些系统性的规律
patterns in what type of examples it is misclassifying.
什么类型的邮件总是被错误分类
And often by doing that, this
经常地 这样做之后
is the process that would inspire
这个过程能启发你
you to design new features.
构造新的特征变量
Or they'll tell you whether the
或者告诉你
current things or current
现在
shortcomings of the system
这个系统的短处
and give you the inspiration you
然后启发你
need to come up with improvements to it.
如何去提高它
Concretely, here's a specific example.
具体地说 这里有一个例子
Let's say you've built a spam
假设你正在构造一个
classifier and you
垃圾邮件分类器
have 500 examples in
你拥有500个实例
your cross-validation set.
在交叉验证集中
And let's say in this example, that the
假设在这个例子中
algorithm has a very high error
该算法有非常高的误差率
rate, and it misclassifies a
它错误分类了
hundred of these cross-validation examples.
一百个交叉验证实例
So what I do is manually
所以我要做的是
examine these 100 errors, and
人工检查这100个错误
manually categorize them, based
然后手工为它们分类
on things like what type
基于例如
of email it is and
这些是什么类型的邮件
what cues or what features you
哪些变量
think might have helped the algorithm classify them incorrectly.
能帮助这个算法来正确分类它们
So, specifically, by what
明确地说
type of email it is,
通过鉴定这是哪种类型的邮件
you know, if I look through these
通过检查
hundred errors I may find
这一百封错误分类的邮件
that maybe the most
我可能会发现
common types of spam
最容易被误分类的邮件
emails in misclassifies are maybe
可能是
emails on pharmacy, so basically
有关药物的邮件
these are emails trying to
基本上这些邮件都是卖药的
sell drugs, maybe emails that are
或者
trying to sell replicas -
卖仿品的
those are those fake watches fake you know, random things.
比如卖假表
Maybe have some emails trying to steal passwords.
或者一些骗子邮件
These are also called phishing emails.
又叫做钓鱼邮件
But that's another big category of emails and maybe other categories.
等等
So, in terms
所以
of classify what type of email
在检查哪些邮件被错误分类的时候
it is, I would actually go through
我会看一看每封邮件
and count up, you know, of
数一数 比如
my 100 emails, maybe I
在这100封错误归类的邮件中
find that twelve of the
我发现有12封
mislabeled emails are pharma emails.
错误归类的邮件是和卖药有关的邮件
And maybe four of them
4封
are emails trying to sell
是推销仿品的
replicas, they sell fake watches or something.
推销假表或者别的东西
And maybe I find that 53
然后我发现
of them are these,
有53封邮件
what's called phishing emails, basically emails
是钓鱼邮件
trying to persuade you to
诱骗你
give them your password, and 31 emails are other types of emails.
告诉他们你的密码 剩下的31封别的类型的邮件
And it's by counting up the
通过算出
number of emails in these
每个类别中
different categories that you might
不同的邮件数
discover, for example, that the
你可能会发现 比如
algorithm is doing really particularly
该算法在
poorly on emails trying to
区分钓鱼邮件的时候
steal passwords, and that
总是表现得很差
may suggest that it might
这说明
be worth your effort to look
你应该花更多的时间
more carefully at that type
来研究这种类型的邮件
of email, and see if
然后
you can come up with better features
看一看你是否能通过构造更好的特征变量
to categorize them correctly.
来正确区分这种类型的邮件
And also, what I might
同时
do is look at what cues,
我要做的是
or what features, additional features
看一看哪些特征变量
might have helped the algorithm classify the emails.
可能会帮助算法正确地分类邮件
So let's say that some of
我们假设
our hypotheses about things or
能帮助我们提高
features that might help us
邮件分类表现
classify emails better are trying
的方法是
to detect deliberate misspellings versus
检查有意的拼写错误
unusual email routing versus unusual, you know,
不寻常的邮件路由来源
spamming punctuation, such as
以及垃圾邮件特有的标点符号方式
people use a lot of exclamation marks.
比如很多感叹号
And once again, I would manually
与之前一样
go through and let's say
我会手动地浏览这些邮件
I find five cases of
假设有5封这种类型的邮件
this, and 16 of
16封这种类型的
this, and 32 of this and
32封这种类型的
a bunch of other types of emails as well.
以及一些别的类型的
And if this is what
如果
you get on your cross validation
这就是你从交叉验证中得到的结果
set then it really tells
那么
you that, you know, maybe deliberate spelling
这可能说明
is a sufficiently rare phenomenon
有意地拼写错误出现频率较少
that maybe is not really worth
这可能并不值得
all your time trying to write
你花费时间
algorithms to detect that.
去编写算法来检测这种类型的邮件
But if you find a lot
但是如果你发现
of spammers are using, you
很多的垃圾邮件
know, unusual punctuation then
都有不一般的标点符号规律
maybe that's a strong sign
那么这是一个很强的特征
that it might actually be
说明你应该
worth your while to spend
花费你的时间
the time to develop more sophisticated
去构造基于标点符号的
features based on the punctuation.
更加复杂的特征变量
So, this sort of error
因此
analysis which is really
这种类型的误差分析
the process of manually examining
是一种手动检测的过程
the mistakes that the algorithm
检测算法可能会犯的错误
makes, can often help
这经常能够帮助你
guide you to the most fruitful avenues to pursue.
找到更为有效的手段
And this also explains why I
这也解释了为什么
often recommend implementing a quick
我总是推荐先实践一种
and dirty implementation of an algorithm.
快速即便不完美的算法
What we really want to do
我们真正想要的是
is figure out what are
找出什么类型的邮件
the most difficult examples for an algorithm to classify.
是这种算法最难分类出来的
And very often for different
对于不同的算法
algorithms, for different learning algorithms,
不同的机器学习算法
they'll often find, you
它们
know, similar categories of examples difficult.
所遇到的问题一般总是相同的
And by having a quick and
通过实践一些快速
dirty implementation, that's often a
即便不完美的算法
quick way to let you
你能够更快地
identify some errors and quickly
找到错误的所在
identify what are the
并且快速找出算法难以处理的例子
hard examples so that you can focus your efforts on those.
这样你就能集中精力在这些真正的问题上
Lastly, when developing learning algorithms,
最后 在构造机器学习算法时
one other useful tip is
另一个有用的小窍门是
to make sure that you have
保证你自己
a way, that you have a
保证你能有一种
numerical evaluation of your learning algorithm.
数值计算的方式来评估你的机器学习算法
Now what I mean by that is that
我这么说的意思是
if you're developing a learning algorithm,
如果你在构造一个学习算法
it is often incredibly helpful
如果你能有一种
if you have a way of
评估你算法的方法
evaluating your learning algorithm
这是非常有用的
that just gives you back a single real number.
一种用数字说话的评估方法
Maybe accuracy, maybe error.
你的算法可能精确 可能有错
But the single real number that tells you how well your learning algorithm is doing.
但是它能准确的告诉你你的算法到底表现有多好
I'll talk more about this specific
在接下来的课程中
concepts in later videos, but here's a specific example.
我会更详细的讲述这个概念 但是先看看这个例子
Let's say we are trying to
假设我们试图
decide whether or not we
决定是否应该
should treat words like discount,
把像"discount""discounts""discounter""discountring"
discounts, discounter, discounting, as the same word.
这样的单词都视为等同
So maybe one way to
一种方法
do that is to just
是检查这些单词的
look at the first few characters in a word.
开头几个字母
Like, you know, if you just look at
比如
the first few characters of
当你在检查这些单词开头几个字母的时候
a word, then you figure
你发现
out that maybe all of these
这几个单词
words are roughly -   have similar meanings.
大概可能有着相同的意思
In natural language processing, the
在自然语言处理中
way that this is done is
这种方法
actually using a type of software called stemming software.
是通过一种叫做词干提取的软件实现的
If you ever want to do
如果你想自己来试试
this yourself, search on a
你可以
web search engine for the
在网上搜索一下
Porter Stemmer and that
"Porter Stemmer(波特词干提取法)"
would be, you know, one reasonable piece of
这是在词干提取方面
software for doing this sort
一个比较不错的软件
of stemming, which will let
这个软件会
you treat all of these discount,
将单词"discount""discounts"以及等等
discounts, and so on as the same word.
都视为同一个单词
But using a stemming software
但是这种词干提取软件
that basically looks at the
只会检查
first few alphabets of the
单词的头几个字母
word more or less, it can help but it can hurt.
这有用 但是也可能会造成一些问题
And it can hurt because, for
因为
example, this software may
举个例子
mistake the words universe and
因为这个软件会把单词"universe(宇宙)"
university as being the
和"university(大学)"
same thing because, you know,
也视为同一个单词
these two words start off
因为
with very similar characters, with the same alphabets.
这两个单词开头的字母是一样的
So if you're trying
因此
to decide whether or not
当你在决定
to use stemming software for
是否应该使用词干提取软件用来分类
a stem classifier, it is not always easy to tell.
这总是很难说清楚
And in particular, error analysis
特别地
may not actually be helpful
误差分析
for deciding if this
也并不能帮助你决定
sort of stemming idea is a good idea.
词干提取是不是一个好的方法
Instead, the best way
与之相对地 最好的方法
to figure out if using stemming
来发现词干提取软件
software is good to help
对你的分类器
your classifier is if you
到底有没有用
have a way to very quickly
是迅速地着手试一试
just try it and see if it works.
来看看它表现到底怎么样
And in order to do this,
为了这么做
having a way to numerically
通过数值来评估你的算法
evaluate your algorithm, is going to be very helpful.
是非常有用的
Concretely, maybe the most
具体地说
natural thing to do is
自然而然地
to look at the cross validation
你应该通过交叉验证
error of the algorithm's performance with and without stemming.
来验证不用词干提取与用词干提取的算法的错误率
So, if you run your
因此
algorithm without stemming and you
如果你不在你的算法中使用词干提取
end up with, let's say,
然后你得到 比如
five percent classification error, and
5%的分类错误率
you re-run it and you
然后你再使用词干提取来运行你的算法
end up with, let's say, three
你得到 比如
percent classification error, then this
3%的分类错误
decrease in error very quickly
那么这很大的减少了错误发生
allows you to decide that,
于是你决定
you know, it looks like using stemming is a good idea.
词干提取是一个好的办法
For this particular problem, there's
就这个特定的问题而言
a very natural single real
这里有一个数量的评估数字
number evaluation metric, namely, the cross validation error.
即交差验证错误率
We'll see later, examples where coming
我们以后会发现
up with this, sort of, single
这个例子中的评估数字
row number evaluation metric may need a little bit more work.
还需要一些处理
But as we'll see in
但是
the later video, doing so would
我们可以在今后的课程中看到
also then let you
这么做还是会让你
make these decisions much more quickly
能更快地做出决定
of, say, whether or not to use stemming.
比如 是否使用词干提取
And just this one more quick example.
再说一个例子
Let's say that you're also trying
假设
to decide whether or not
你在想是否应该
to distinguish between upper versus lower case.
区分单词的大小写
So, you know, is the red
比如
mom with uppercase M
单词"mom" 大写的"M"
versus lower case m,
和小写的"m"
I mean, should that be treated as
它们应该被视作
the same word or as different words?
同一个单词还是不同的单词
Should these be treated as the same feature or as different features?
它们应该被视作相同的特征变量还是不同的
And so once again,
再说一次
because we have a way
因为我们有一种
to evaluate our algorithm, if
能够评估我们算法的方法
you try this out here, if
如果你在这里试一试
I stop distinguishing upper
如果我不区分
and lower case, maybe I
大小写
end up with 3.2%
最后得到3.2%的错误率
error and I find that
然后我发现
therefore this does worse
这个表现的较差些
than, you know, if I use only
如果
stemming, and so this lets
如果我只用了词干提取
me very quickly decide to go
这之后我再思考
ahead and to distinguish or to
是否要区分
not distinguish between upper and lower case.
大小写
So when you' re developing
因此当你在
a learning algorithm, very often
构造学习算法的时候
you'll be trying out lots of
你总是会去尝试
new ideas and lots of new versions of your learning algorithm.
很多新的想法 实现出很多版本的学习算法
If every time you try
如果每一次
out a new idea if you
你实践新想法的时候
end up manually examining a
你都手动地检测
bunch of examples, you begin to
这些例子
see better or worse, you
去看看是表现差还是表现好
know, that's going to make it
那么这很难让你
really hard to make decisions
做出决定
on do you use stemming or not.
到底是否使用词干提取
Do you distinguish upper or lowercase or not?
是否区分大小写
But by having a single rule
但是通过一个
number evaluation metric, you can
量化的数值评估
then just look and see oh, did the error go up or go down?
你可以看看这个数字 误差是变大还是变小了
And you can use that much
你可以通过它
more rapidly, try out
更快地实践
new ideas and almost right
你的新想法
away tell if your new
它基本上非常直观地告诉你
idea has improved or worsened
你的想法是提高了算法表现
the performance of the learning algorithm
还是让它变得更坏
and this will let
这会大大提高
you often make much faster progress.
你实践算法时的速度
So the recommended, strongly recommended
所以我强烈推荐
way to do error analysis is
在交叉验证集上来实施误差分析
on the cross validation set rather than the test set.
而不是在测试集上
But, you know, there are
但是
people that will do this on
还是有一些人
the test set even though that's
会在测试集上来做误差分析
definitely a less mathematically appropriate
即使这从数学上讲
set of your list, recommended what
是不合适的
you think to do than to
所以我还是推荐你
do error analysis on your
在交叉验证向量上
cross validation sector.
来做误差分析
So, to wrap up this video, when starting
总结一下
on the new machine learning problem, what
当你在研究一个新的机器学习问题时
I almost always recommend is
我总是推荐你
to implement a quick and
实现一个较为简单快速
dirty implementation of your learning algorithm.
即便不是那么完美的算法
And I've almost never seen
我几乎从未见过
anyone spend too little time on this quick and dirty implementation.
人们这样做
I pretty much only ever see
大家经常干的事情是
people spend much too much
花费大量的时间
time building their first, you know,
在构造算法上
supposedly quick and dirty implementations.
构造他们以为的简单的方法
So really, don't worry about
因此
it being too quick, or don't worry about it being too dirty.
不要担心你的算法太简单 或者太不完美
But really implement something as
而是尽可能快地
quickly as you can, and once
实现你的算法
you have the initial implementation this
当你有了初始的实现之后
is then a powerful tool for
它会变成一个非常有力的工具
deciding where to spend your
来帮助你决定
time next, because first we
下一步的做法
can look at the errors it makes,
因为我们可以先看看算法造成的错误
and do this sort of error analysis
通过误差分析
to see what mistakes it makes
来看看他犯了什么错
and use that to inspire further development.
然后来决定优化的方式
And second, assuming your
另一件事是
quick and dirty implementation incorporated a
假设你有了一个快速而不完美的算法实现
single real number evaluation metric, this
又有一个数值的评估数据
can then be a vehicle for
这会帮助你
you to try out different ideas
尝试新的想法
and quickly see if the
快速地发现
different ideas you're trying out
你尝试的这些想法
are improving the performance of
是否能够提高算法的表现
your algorithm and therefore let
从而
you maybe much more quickly
你会更快地
make decisions about what things
做出决定
to fold, and what things to
在算法中放弃什么 吸收什么
incorporate into your learning algorithm.